<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DP on Tracey Hoang</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com/tags/dp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DP on Tracey Hoang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 14:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.example.com/tags/dp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Divide an array into 3 subsets with equal sum - Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/threesubsetequalsum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 14:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/threesubsetequalsum/</guid>
      <description>Source code
Description Given an array arr of n integers (n &amp;gt; 0). Find out that is it possible to divide the given array into three sets with equal sums.
For example, array arr = {1, 1, 2, 2, 3, 3} can be divided into 3 subsets with equal sum = 4 as follows: {1, 3}, {1, 3} and {2, 2}; while array arr = {1, 1, 2} can not be divided into such 3 subsets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longest Common Subsequence (LCS) - Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/lcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 14:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/lcs/</guid>
      <description>Source code
We are going to solve this problem by using Dynamic Programming with memoisation and tabulation techniques.
Problem Description The longest common subsequence (LCS) problem is to compute the length of a longest subsequence common to all given sequences. A subsequence is a sequence that appears in the same relative order, but not necessarily contiguous. For example, the LCS of two sequence {1,2,3} and {1,3,5} is {1,3}, and has the length is 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coin Change Problem - Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/dynamicprogramming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/dynamicprogramming/</guid>
      <description>Source code
Dynamic programming solves the complex problem by breaking it into simpler sub-problems, solving each of those once, and storing their solution for later use. Dynamic programming uses memoisation and tabulation technique for improving its performance.
Memoisation is a technique of optimisation by storing the solutions of function calls and returning the cached result when the same inputs are called again.
Tabulation is an approach by first filling up a table, then solving the original problem based on the solutions in this table.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>