<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>go on Tracey Hoang</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in go on Tracey Hoang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Tracey. I am a self-taught software engineer with applied mathematics background. After going through A Tour of Go, I found that Go was actually a neat and simple language to learn and started to develop more interest in programming. While still in my learning journey, I create this blog to share interesting problems and projects that I have done in Go, as well as some other useful resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface Example in Go</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/interfaceexample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/interfaceexample/</guid>
      <description>Source code
This is an example of struct, method, and interface.
I define an interface named geometry that has area() and perim() method signitures.
type geometry interface { area() float64 perim() float64 } I also define 3 other types circle, rectangle and triangle that implement geometry interface. For example, type circle implements all the geometry interface methods as follows.
type circle struct { radius float64 } func (c circle) area() float64 { return math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balanced Binary Search Tree - AVL Tree</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/balancedbst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 23:10:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/balancedbst/</guid>
      <description>Source code
Introduction AVL tree is a height-balanced binary search tree (BST). In an AVL tree, every node maintains a balance factor, which is defind as follows
balance_factor := height(left_subtree) - height(right_subtree)According to definition of a balanced tree, the balance factor of every node in the AVL tree is either -1, 0, or 1. When an insertion or deletion operation is performed, the tree&amp;rsquo;s height may change, so do the balance factors at nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search Tree - Part III</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/bst-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/bst-others/</guid>
      <description>Source code
Fetch maximum value Maximum value of a BST is the value of the most right node
func FetchMax(t *treeNode) int { if t.Right == nil { return t.Value } return FetchMax(t.Right) } Return value: 14
Fetch minimum value Minimum value of a BST is the value of the most left node
func FetchMin(t *treeNode) int { if t.Left == nil { return t.Value } return FetchMin(t.Left) } Return: 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search Tree - Part II</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/traverse-bst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 22:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/traverse-bst/</guid>
      <description>Source code
A traversal is a process of visiting all the nodes in a tree. We can categorise tree&amp;rsquo;s traversal algorithms into 2 groups: depth-first traversal and breadth-first traversal.
 Depth-first traversal: includes PreOrder traversal, InOrder traversal, and PostOrder traversal. Breadth-first traversal: the level order traversal. In this traversal, we visit the node by levels from top to bottom, and from left to right.  Let have a look at implementations of those traversal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search Tree - Part I</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/bst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/bst/</guid>
      <description>Source code
Introduction A Binary Tree is a tree data structure, that consists of nodes. The topmost node in the tree is the root. Every node in a Binary Tree has maximum 2 children, which are referred to as left and right child. A leaf is a node that both its left and right subtrees are empty. A node with only one subtree is called half-leaf. A parent of a node is the node immediately above it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mira Jump</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/project/mirajump/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 21:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/project/mirajump/</guid>
      <description>Source code
Description This is a very simple game modified from Flappy Gopher game from Ebiten. It is written in Go using Ebiten library.
Mira is running her scooter. She is going to meet objects on her way, and jumping over them is the only way to go pass. Every time when she successfully avoids an object she will get one point.
How to play Press space key or left-click when you want to jump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Slack bot in Go using event API - Stock Bot</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/project/stockbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 21:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/project/stockbot/</guid>
      <description>Source code
In this application, we will discuss about stockbot that returns stock prices of a company. The architecture is as follows.
For one who comes to this repository first, I have another repository call weatherbot in which I have described step by step how to build a weatherbot for querying weather conditon of a location. Most of the steps of implementation for two bots are similar, including building a Slack bot user, subscribing to app mentioned event, creating a Go function which is a HTTP handler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Slack bot in Go using event API - Weather Bot</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/project/weatherbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 20:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/project/weatherbot/</guid>
      <description>Source code
In this repository, I&amp;rsquo;m going to create a weatherbot for querying weather condition of a given location. The idea of writing a Slack bot in Go was inspired by rapidloop&amp;rsquo;s slackbot for RTM API. At the moment, Slack platform provides a range of APIs that Slack apps can access to including events API, web API, Audit Logs APIs beside RTM API which was used in rapidloop&amp;rsquo;s implementation. As RTM API is being phased out in favour of events API, in this application, events API will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dining Philosopher problem in Go</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/docs/dining-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 14:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/docs/dining-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Source code
I found that it is an excellent example about Go concurrency and synchronization.
Problem description There are 5 philosophers having their dinner at a round table with one chopstick between each adjacent pair of philosophers. A philosopher can only eat when they have both left and right chopsticks. In other words, while one philosopher is eating, his two adjacent friends have to wait. After eating he puts both chopsticks down to let the others eat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
